A Guide to the Thomas H. Arthur Papers, 1953-2018: SC 0088
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Thomas H. Arthur Papers,
1953-2018
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Arthur, Thomas H.
SC 0088
2.42 cubic feet; 8 boxes (including 1 four-flap enclosure)
The Thomas H. Arthur Papers, 1953-2018, consist of eight boxes (2.42 cubic feet) of personal correspondence, manuscripts, theater programs, photographs, and notes written by Dr. Thomas H. Arthur, JMU faculty member, and pertaining to actor Melvyn Douglas.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Thomas H. Arthur made an initial donation of materials to Special Collections in 1987. Arthur donated additional materials, primarily theater programs, in March 2018.
Bio/Historical Note
Thomas H. Arthur joined the staff of James Madison University in 1973, teaching both theater and speech as part of the Department of Communication Arts. He was instrumental in making theater at JMU into a college department. After the Department of Theatre and Dance was formed in 1986 as part of the College of Arts and Letters, Arthur would serve as the department head from 1987-1989. As a professor, he arranged semester abroad trips to London to expose students to British culture as well as professional theater productions. He continued to teach and direct productions at JMU as part of the faculty until his retirement in 2007.
Arthur was a personal friend of actor Melvyn Douglas and his family, and wrote his doctoral thesis about Douglas's involvement in politics. In 1971, Arthur also collaborated with Douglas, at Douglas' request, to write his autobiography, See You at the Movies: The Autobiography of Melvyn Douglas.
Melvyn Douglas was born Melvyn Hesselberg, on April 5, 1901 in Macon, Georgia. He began his theatrical career in 1917, and adopted the name 'Douglas' some time prior to his movie debut. During his career he was a star of the screen, stage, and television. He was the first male actor to win a Tony Award, an Emmy Award, and an Oscar. In addition to acting, Douglas served in both world wars and was active in politics. In 1940 he became the first actor to serve as a delegate to the Democratic National Convention. He married in 1931 and died in New York City on August 4, 1981. A portion of this collection includes letters and notes relating to Dr. Arthur's book, See You at the Movies: The Autobiography of Melvyn Douglas (Lanham, Md. University Press of America, 1986).
Scope and Content
The Thomas H. Arthur Papers, 1953-2018, consist of eight boxes (2.42 cubic feet). The collection is arranged into two series, with two subseries each: 1. Theater Programs and Printed Materials, 1.1 Playbills, 1.2 Theater Print Materials, 2. Scholarship and Teaching, 2.1 Melvyn Douglas Research, 2.2 Study Abroad Semester Materials. The largest part of the collection comprises the playbills and theater print materials from both domestic and international theaters. The collection also includes Arthur's research into the life of actor Melvyn Douglas, including photographs, handwritten notes, and correspondence provided by Douglas and his family to inform Arthur's research.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series:
Series 1. Theater Programs and Printed Materials, 1953-2018
Series 1.1 Playbills, 1953-2018
Series 1.2 Theater Print Materials, 1962-2005
Series 2. Scholarship and Teaching, 1970-2014
Series 2.1 Melvyn Douglas Research, 1970-1982
Series 2.2 Study Abroad Semester Materials, 1979-2014
Each series is arranged chronologically except Series 1.1 Playbills which is arranged alphabetically by theater production.
Related Material
Wisconsin Historical Society, Melvyn Douglas, Melvyn Douglas Papers, 1892-1983.
School of Theatre and Dance Records, 1930-2011 (bulk 1981-1993), UA 0045, Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University, Harrisonburg, VA.
Bibliography
James Madison University. The School of Theatre and Dance. http://www.jmu.edu/theatre/pdf/backstages07.pdf. Accessed October 2019.
James Madison University. Bluestone. Harrisonburg, VA: 1988. James Madison University Special Collections.
Index Terms
Genre and Form Terms:
Playbills; Programs (documents); Letters (correspondence); Photographs; Printed Ephemera; Itineraries; Interviews
- Series 1: Theater Programs and Printed Materials, 1953-2018
  Scope and Content
  Series 1: Theater Programs and Printed Materials, 1953-2018, is separated into two subseries: theater programs and printed materials related to many of the shows represented in the playbills. The theater programs document the many plays and musicals that Arthur attended, with the majority playing in London and on Broadway and spanning more than 60 years. Playbills of note include programs from award-winning shows such as Hamilton, Kiss of the Spider Woman, The Lion King, My Fair Lady, and Cats, programs from productions that feature actors including Ian McKellan, Patrick Stewart, Catherine Tate, Judi Dench, Viola Davis, and Gary Oldman, and programs from many versions of classic Shakespeare plays, such as Twelfth Night and Hamlet. The theater print material subseries comprises other theater-related pamphlets and programs, most of which are either souvenir brochures or pamphlets that include calendars for a particular season.
  - Subseries 1.1: Playbills, 1953-2018
    - 2 Pianos, 4 Hands - American Theatre College Festival XXX, 1981-2018 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 2 Pianos, 4 Hands, 1999
      - 9 Parts of Desire, 2006
      - 21st Annual Humana Festival of New American Plays, 1997
      - The 25th Annual Putnam County Spelling Bee, 2006
      - 40 Years On, 1984
      - 42nd Street, 1983
      - 84 Charing Cross Road, 1981
      - Absolute Hell, 1995
      - Accidental Death of an Anarchist, 1981
      - Ain't Misbehavin, 1985
      - Ajax, 1986
      - Aladdin, 2016
      - Alice, 2003
      - All My Sons, 1981
      - All My Sons, 2018
      - Amadeus, 1981
      - The American College Theatre Festival XVI, 1984
      - The American College Theatre Festival XXVI, 1994
      - The American College Theatre Festival XXX, 1998
    - Angels in America - Avenue Q, 1962-2015 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Angels in America, 1994
      - Anna in the Tropics, 2004
      - Annie, 1981
      - Annie, 2013
      - Animal Farm, 1986
      - Antony and Cleopatra, 2008
      - Anything Goes, 2003
      - The Archbishop's Ceiling, 1986
      - Arms and the Man, 1981
      - Art, 1996
      - Art, 2000-2001
      - As You Like It, 1962
      - As You Like It, 1981-1982
      - The Audience, 2015
      - August: Osage County, 2008
      - Avenue Q, 2004
    - Ballroom - Big River, 1961-2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Ballroom, 1978
      - Barefoot in the Park, 1965
      - ΒΑΤΡΑΧΟΙ, 2002-2003
      - The Bay at Nice and Wrecked Eggs, 1986
      - The Beastly Beatitudes of Balthazar B, 1982
      - Beatlemania, 1978
      - The Beauty Queen of Leenane, 1998
      - As Bees in Honey Drown, 1997
      - Bells are Ringing, 1961
      - Benefactors, 1984
      - Big River: The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn, 1986
    - Billy Bishop Goes to War - By George...It's Gershwin, 1963-2010, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Billy Bishop Goes to War, 1982
      - The Blacks, undated
      - Blackbird, 2006
      - Blood Brothers, 1988
      - Bloody Poetry, 1984
      - Blue Man Group "Tubes", 1992
      - Blue Surge, 2001
      - Bobrauschenbergamerica, 2009-2010
      - Bookworms, 2010
      - Bouncers, undated
      - The Boyfriend, 1984
      - Breaking the Code, 1986
      - Breaking the Silence, 1984
      - Brigadoon, 1963
      - Brothers Karamazov, 1981
      - By George...It's Gershwin, 1987
    - La Cage Aux Folles - Children of a Lesser God, 1978-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - La Cage Aux Folles, 1986
      - Canterbury Tales, undated
      - Can't Pay? Won't Pay!, 1981
      - Carmen, 1996-1997
      - Carmen Jones, 1991
      - Cats, 1999
      - The Caucasian Chalk Circle, 1997
      - Champagne Charlie, 1984
      - Chapter Two, 1978
      - The Cherry Orchard, 1997
      - Chicago, 1999
      - Children of a Lesser God, 1980
    - Chinese State Circus - Coriolanus, 1984-2006, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Chinese State Circus, 1995-1996
      - Chopin Recital with Maciej Poliszewski, undated
      - A Chorus of Disapproval, 1986
      - City of Angels, 1991
      - The Clean House, 2006
      - Closer, 1997
      - Cloud Nine, 1997
      - The Color Wheel, 1995
      - Company, 1996
      - The Complete Works of William Shakespeare, 1992
      - Copenhagen, 1999
      - Coriolanus, 1984
      - Coriolanus, 1996
    - Corpse! - Dylan, 1964-2011, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Corpse!, 1984
      - Cosi' Fan Tutte`, undated
      - The Count of Monte Cristo, 2004
      - The Country Club, undated
      - The Country Wife, undated
      - Cowgirls, 1996
      - The Cripple of Inishman, 1997-1998
      - Curse of the Starving Class, 1979
      - Cyrano, 1995
      - Cyrano de Bergerac, 1997
      - Dance of Love and Death, 1981
      - Dancing at Lughnasa, 2011
      - Dangerous Corner, undated
      - David Mamet: "Bobby Gould in Hell" Reading, undated
      - A Day at the Opera, A Night at the Races, 1984
      - Dial M for Murder, 1983-1984
      - Dialogues Des Carmelites, 1999-2000
      - Les Dindes Galantes, 2006
      - Don Giovanni, 1984
      - Don Juan, 1981
      - Doonesbury, 1983
      - Driving Miss Daisy, 1988
      - The Drowsy Chaperone, 2006
      - Dylan, 1964
    - East of Eden - Evita, 1981-2018 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - East of Eden, 2014-2015
      - Eastern Standard, 1988
      - Edinburgh Military Tattoo, 1981
      - Educating Rita, 1981
      - Eleemosynary, 1993
      - English Chamber Orchestra Concert Series, 1984
      - English Chamber Orchestra Concert Series, 1997
      - Equus, 2017
      - Evita, 1980
      - Evita, 1981
    - Fair Maid - Frankie and Johnny in the Clair de Lune, 1975-2016 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - The Fair Maid of the West, 1987
      - Falstaff and Hal, 1986
      - A Few Good Men, 1994
      - Finian's Rainbow, 2016
      - First Monday in October, 1975
      - Follies, 2001
      - Follow the Orange and Blue Road, 1998
      - The Fool, 1981
      - Fool for Love, 1983
      - Frankie and Johnny in the Clair de Lune, 1988
      - Frankie and Johnny in the Clair de Lune, 1992
    - Galileo - De La Guarda, 1981-2014, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Galileo, 1986
      - A Gentleman's Guide to Love and Murder, 2014
      - Gianni Scicchi and Pagliacci, 2004
      - Gibraltar, 2013
      - The Glass Menagerie, 1995
      - The Glass Menagerie, 2007
      - The Glass Menagerie, 2010
      - The Goat (or Who is Sylvia?), 2002
      - Godot-Ra Varva, undated
      - Good People, 2011
      - The Gospel at Colonus, 1990
      - Grease, 2000
      - The Green Bird, 2000
      - Groucho at Large, 1981
      - De La Guarda, undated
    - Half a Sixpence - Henry IV, 1962-2016 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Half a Sixpence, 1966
      - Hametz, 1995
      - Hamilton, 2016
      - Hamlet, 1981
      - Hamlet, 1992
      - Hamlet, 1988
      - Hamlet, 1997
      - Hamlet Variations, 2004
      - Handel Opera, 1984
      - Happy New Year, 1979
      - Harvey, 2015
      - Heartbreak House, 2017
      - Hedwig and the Angry Inch, 1999
      - The Heidi Chronicles, 1989
      - Henry IV, 1962
      - Henry IV, 2004
    - Henry IV - Italian American Reconciliation, 1975-2011, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Henry IV, 1994
      - Henry VIII, 2002
      - Herr Puntila Und Sein Knecht Matti, 1975
      - High Spirits, undated
      - The Hired Man, 1984
      - Hogan's Goat, undated
      - The Homecoming, 1997
      - The House of Blue Leaves, 1986
      - The Hypochondriac, 1981
      - An Ideal Husband, 1996
      - An Iliad, 2011
      - I'm Not Rappaport, 1986
      - An Inspector Calls, undated
      - Intimate Exchanges, 1985
      - Italian American Rconciliation, undated
    - Jack: A Night on the Town - Little Hotel on the Side, 1981-2015, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jack: A Night on the Town with John Barrymore, 1994
      - Jelly's Last Jam, 1992
      - Joyce, 2007
      - Judith: A Parting from the Body, 2010
      - The Kingfisher, 1981
      - King Hedley II, 2001
      - The King and I, 2015
      - King Richard III (The Big Dick), undated
      - Kiss Me, Kate, undated
      - Kiss of the Spider Woman, 1994
      - Lady in the Dark, 1997
      - The Last Nights of Ballyhoo, 1997
      - Les Miserables, 1985
      - A Letter of Resignation, 1997
      - The Life and Adventures of Nicholas Nickleby, 1982
      - The Life of Henry the Fift., 1997
      - The Light in the Piazza, 2005
      - The Lion King, 2014
      - A Little Bit Like You, 2003
      - The Little Dog Laughed, 2006
      - A Little Hotel on the Side, 1984
    - Little Me - Love and Understanding, 1983-2008 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Little Me, 1984
      - The Little Mermaid, 2008
      - Little Shop of Horrors, 1983
      - Long Day's Journey into Night, 2003
      - Loot, 1984
      - Love's Labor's Lost, 1987
      - Love's Labour's Lost, 1994
      - Love and Understanding, 1997
      - The Lucky Chance, 1984
    - Macbeth - Mary Poppins, 1965-2012, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Macbeth, 1965
      - Macbeth, 1989
      - Madame Melville, 2000
      - A Madhouse in Goa, 1989
      - The Madness of George III, 1992
      - Macbeth, 2004
      - Madame Butterfly, 1984
      - Madame Butterfly, 1988
      - The Magic Flute, 1997
      - The Magistrate, 1986
      - Making it Happen, undated
      - Malfi, 1995
      - Mamma Mia, 2001
      - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom, 1985
      - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom, undated
      - Marat, 1997
      - Marcel Marceau, 1965
      - Maria Callas: Master Class, 1996
      - The Marriage of Figaro, 1991
      - Mary Poppins, 2012
    - Measure for Measure - The Mystery of Edwin Drood, 1959-2011, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Measure for Measure, undated
      - Medea, 2000
      - Merchant of Venice, 1962
      - The Merry Widow, 1980
      - The Merry Wives of Windsor, 1997
      - Metamorpheses, 2002
      - Metamorpheses, 2010
      - Of Mice and Men, 1999
      - The Midnight Eucharist, 1984
      - A Midsummer Night's Dream, 1985
      - Million Dollar Quartet, 2011
      - Misalliance, 1995
      - Misery, 1992
      - Monteith and Rand, 1978
      - Much Ado About Nothing, 1981
      - Mutabilitie, 1997
      - My Children! My Africa!, undated
      - My Fair Lady, 1959
      - My Fair Lady, 1981
      - My Fair Lady, 2002
      - My Giddy Aunt, 1968
      - The Mystery of Edwin Drood, 1986
    - National Black Arts Festival - Nunsense, 1960-2014, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - National Black Arts Festival, 1992
      - National Symphony Orchestra: All Beethoven, 1980
      - Newsies, 2013
      - A New Way to Pay Old Debts, 1984
      - New York Philharmonic Young People's Concert, 1958
      - New York Philharmonic Young People's Concert, 1960
      - New York Philharmonic Young People's Concert, 1960
      - 'night, Mother, 1983
      - Nine, 2003
      - No Frost 17, undated
      - Noises Off, 1984
      - Noises Off, 2004
      - No Man's Land and Waiting for Godot, 2014
      - Nothing Sacred, 1989
      - Nunsense, undated
    - Oedipus - Outrage, 1962-2013, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Oedipus, undated
      - Oklahoma!, 2002
      - Old Times, undated
      - Old Wicked Songs, 1996
      - Oliver!, 1963
      - Oliver!, 1964
      - Once on this Island, 1991
      - The O'Neill Plays, 1988
      - One Mo' Time, 1981
      - On the Twentieth Century, 1978
      - On Your Toes, 1984
      - The Oresteia, 1981
      - Orson's Shadow, 2005
      - Othello, 1962
      - Othello, 1979
      - The Other Place, 2013
      - O'Toole Reading, 1996
      - Our Lady of 121st Street, 2003
      - Outrage, 2011
    - Passion Play - Punch Henry's Jazz Funeral, 1962-2016, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Passion Play, 1984
      - Pebuzop Tarkastaja, 1989
      - People Show, 1981
      - Pericles, 2005
      - Peter Pan, 2016
      - The Petition, 1986
      - Phedra, 1984
      - Photo Finish, undated
      - The Piano Lesson, 1990
      - The Pirates of Penzance and The Mikado, 1981
      - The Pixie Led, 1989
      - Playland, 1994
      - Playland, undated
      - The Pope's Wedding and Saved, 1984
      - The Premise, 1962
      - Present Laughter, 1981
      - Present Laughter, 1996
      - The Prince's Play, 1996
      - The Prisoner of Second Avenue, 2010
      - Private Eyes, 1970
      - Private Eyes, 2002
      - Punch Henry's Jazz Funeral, 1981
    - Quartermaine's Terms - Russian Classical Ballet, 1962-2004, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Quartermaine's Terms, 1982
      - The Queen and the Rebels, 1982
      - Red Cross, undated
      - Rent, 1998
      - Restoration, 1981
      - Richard II, 1962
      - Richard II, 1987
      - Richard III, 1962
      - The Rise and Fall of Little Voice, 1992
      - Rules for Good Manners in the Modern World, 2004
      - The Russian Classical Ballet, undated
    - Sadler's Wells Royal Ballet - Shirley Valentine, 1962-2005, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Sadler's Wells Royal Ballet, 1984
      - Saint Oedipus, 2005
      - Salome, 1989
      - Sarafina, 1989
      - The Scarlet Pimpernel, 2002
      - The School for Scandal, 1962
      - The School for Scandal, 1984
      - The School for Wives, 1997
      - A Servant to Two Masters, undated
      - Seven Guitars, 1996
      - Sex and Longing, 1996
      - Shadowlands, 1989
      - She Stoops to Conquer, 1984
      - Shirley Valentine, 1989
    - Shoemaker's Holiday - Strip Show, 1962-2017, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - The Shoemaker's Holiday, 1981
      - Shopping and Fucking, 1997
      - Shouting in the Evening, 1997
      - Side Man, 1999
      - The Silver Whistle, 1962-1963
      - Simon Boccanegra, 1981
      - Six Characters in Search of an Author, 1966
      - Six Characters in Search of an Author, 1987
      - Six Degrees of Separation, 1991
      - Skylight, 1997
      - Souvenir, 2017
      - Speed-The-Plow, 1989
      - Spring Awakening, 2008
      - Stage Kiss, 2014
      - Stanley, 1996
      - Steaming, 1981
      - Steaming, 1982
      - Stepping Out, 1984
      - A Streetcar Named Desire, 2017
      - Strip Show, undated
    - The Sum of Us - Sweet Charity, 1986-2009 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - The Sum of Us, 1991
      - The Sum of Us, 1992
      - Sunset Boulevard, 1996
      - Superior Donuts, 2009
      - Swan Lake, 2002
      - Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street, 2006
      - Sweet Charity, 1986
    - Taking a Chance on Love - Thin Wall, 1961-2005, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Taking a Chance on Love, 2000
      - The Tale of the Allergist's Wife, 2005
      - Talking Heads, 2003
      - 廁所的故事 (The Tale of the Toilet), undated
      - Tantalus, 2000
      - The Tempest, 1961
      - The Tempest, 2001
      - Texts for Nothing, undated
      - Theatre of Nations, 1986
      - Theatrical Garden Party, 1984
      - They're Playing Our Song, 1980
      - Things We Do for Love, 1998
      - Thin Wall, undated
    - A Thousand Clowns - Two Trains Running, 1962-2016 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - A Thousand Clowns, 1962
      - Thee Birds Alighting on a Field, 1992
      - Three Men on a Horse, 1987
      - The Threepenny Opera, 2002
      - Timon of Athens, 2004
      - Tiny Alice, undated
      - Today, I am a Fountain Pen, 1985
      - Tons of Money, 1986
      - Tony n' Tina's Wedding, 1988
      - Topdog/Underdog, 2002
      - The Torch-Bearers, 2000
      - Torch Song Trilogy, 1985
      - Translations, 1981
      - The Triumph of Love, 2004
      - TRU, 2016
      - True West, 1983
      - Twelfth Night or What You Will, 1991
      - Twelfe Night, or What You Will/The Tragedie of King Richard the Third, 2014
      - The Two Noble Kingsmen, 2002
      - Two Rooms, 1998
      - Two Trains Running, 1991
    - Under Milk Wood - Volpone, 1981-2004, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Under Milk Wood, 1995
      - Undoing Salk, 2004
      - Urinetown: The Musical, 2001
      - Veterans Day, 1989
      - Village Wooing and 1933, a Portrait of the Year, undated
      - Vivaldi and Bach by Candlelight, 1997
      - Volpone, 1995
    - Wait Until Dark - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?, 1962-2011, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Wait Until Dark, undated
      - Waiting for Godot, 1997
      - The Warsaw Ballet, undated
      - A Walk in the Woods, 1988
      - WarHorse, 2012
      - The Way of the World, 1984
      - The Wedding, 2010
      - West Shore Concerts: The Cleveland Orchestra, 1962
      - When We Dead Awaken, 1990
      - The Whipping Man, 2011
      - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?, 1962
      - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?, 1981
      - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?, 2006
    - Wicked - You Never Can Tell, 1978-2004, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Wicked, 2004
      - Wild Honey, 1984
      - Wild Oats, 1995
      - The Will Rogers Follies: A Life in Rome, 1991
      - Wit, 1999
      - The Witches, undated
      - The Wiz, 1978
      - The Woman in Black, 1989
      - Woman in Mind, 1986
      - Wonderful Town!, 1986
      - Year of the Rooster, undated
      - You Never Can Tell, 1987
  - Print Theater Materials, 1962-2005
    Arrangement
    Due to being an oversized item, the Beijing Opera at the Liyuan Theater souvenir brochure was housed in a separate four-flap container.
    - Printed Materials, (Folder 1 of 3), 1962-1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Printed Materials, (Folder 2 of 3), 1996-2015, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Printed Materials, (Folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - The Beijing Opera at the Liyuan Theater, undated (Box 8)
- Series 2: Scholarship and Teaching, 1970-2014
  Series 2: Scholarship and Teaching, 1979-2014, is separated into two-subseries: materials relating to Arthur's research on Melvyn Douglas and material from semesters abroad in London and Italy. The former consists of correspondence, notes and manuscripts, theater programs, and photographs related to Arthur's research for his dissertation abd biography on Melvyn Douglas. Some items of interest include a letter sent February 10, 1972 from actor Robert Redford to Melvyn Douglas, Douglas' handwritten notes for Arthur's book, theater programs that detail Melvyn Douglas's early performances in various theaters throughout the Midwest, and photographs of Melvyn Douglas (or family members of Douglas) that Thomas H. Arthur used in his biography of Douglas. The semester abroad sub-series consists of materials from Arthur's study abroad class. Much of the sub-series comprises museum guides and hotel brochures. Some items of interest include photographs taken by a student while on the trip (with some correspondence written on the back dated 1984), a photograph of Thomas Arthur and three other guests at the Mansion House in London, and an itinerary with dinner programs for the students.
  - Subseries 2.1: Melvyn Douglas Research, 1970-1982
    - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Programs from Early Performances (Folder 1 of 6), 1979 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Programs from Early Performances (Folder 2 of 6), 1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Programs from Early Performances (Folder 3 of 6), 1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Programs from Early Performances (Folder 4 of 6), 1979 (Box 7, Folder 8)